ROSTISLAV VATOLIN

+1 832 983 3965

vatolinrp@gmail.com

Houston, TX

https://www.linkedin.com/in/
rostislav-vatolin/

Expertise in: REST and SOAP APIs, microservice and monolith architectures

Tech stack: Java, Spring Framework, SQL, Docker, Kubernetes, JUnit, Mockito

Cloud providers: Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud Platform

Integrated with: Oracle DB, Azure Cosmos DB (Graph DB), Amazon Dynamo DB, Redis Cache, Gemfire Cache, Azure Service Bus. Apache Kafka

CI/CD: Azure DevOps, Jenkins, Maven, Gradle, Git, Bash, Python

Methodologies and practices: Scrum, Kanban, TDD, DDD

Project management tools: Jira, Rally, Azure Boards

PROFILE

Senior Software Engineer with more than **7 years** of Java development experience. Expertise in the development of **REST** and **SOAP** Java web services, PoC (proof of concept) solutions. Strong knowledge of AWS, GCP, and Azure cloud infrastructures. Propagator of Scrum and Kanban methodologies. Experience in **coaching** a group of students (15+ students). Conducted 50+ technical interviews.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer, Epam, Client in Energy domain, Houston, USA - 2020-Present

Key-developer role. Maintained and enhanced client's heavy backend system of **microservices**, which manages data in Oil and Gas industry. Migrated GCP based services to cloud agnostic solution with primary focus on deployment to Microsoft Azure infrastructure. Was responsible for many **PoC** (proof of concept) work, ADRs (architecture decision records). Configured HPA (horizontal pod autoscaling) for services running on **Kubernetes** in Microsoft Azure Cloud. Refactored services to comply community standards, while contributing them to **open source**. Worked on services under Java and Spring tech stack, fully covered with tests with help of JUnit and Mockito.

Senior Software Engineer, Epam, Client in Telecommunication domain, Belarus - 2019-2020

Developer role. E-commerce project using **SAP Hybris** 1808 with Telco & Media Accelerator 1810. Supported and developed new features using Java 8 and Spring framework in **monolithic architecture**. With every pull request enhanced overall test coverage by 2-5% with help of **JUnit** and **Mockito**. Thanks to CI/CD (Apache Ant and Jenkins) occasionally spotted and debugged issues before they got into production.

Senior Software Engineer, Epam, Client in Building materials domain, Belarus - 2018-2019

Developer role. Developed new functionality using Java 8. Maintained and supported deployment to **AWS Lambda**. Implemented integration with **AWS DynamoDB** using latest AWS java libraries. Utilized configured CI/CD (Maven and Jenkins) to spot issues in non production environment. Set up unit tests with JUnit and Mockito to cover all the business logic.

Software Engineer, Epam, Client in Travel & Hospitality domain, Belarus - 2015-2018

Developer role. Created new functionality (REST APIs), enhanced existing in project's middleware area using Java 8, Spring framework, **Apache Camel**. Ensured enterprise systems integration with **Active MQ** and **Apache Kafka**. Carried deployments of OSGi bundles to on onpremise Redhat JBoss Fuse server. Worked on integration with **Oracle 11** database (created SQL queries), Gemfire cache. Increased test coverage using JUnit and Mockito. Improved CI/CD using Maven, Gradle, Jenkins.

EDUCATION

Belarusian State University — Bachelor degree in Computer Science

INTERESTS

Architecture, high-load systems, CI/CD, Clean code, tech literature.